Guide to the Stanford Honors Essay in Humanities
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Honors Essay in Humanities
1951-2006
SC1222
Stanford University. Humanities Special Program.
3 Linear feet
Stanford Honor Essay in Humanities, bound volumes.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
Stanford Honor Essay in Humanities, bound volumes.
Access Terms
Essays.; Humanities; Humanities--Study and teaching--California --Stanford.; Humanities--United States.; Stanford Humanities Center
Collection Contents
- Essays
  - J. M. Keynes, Vision and Technique/ Helen Phillips, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Graham Greene, the Major Novels/ Lynette Kohn, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Pacifism and Democracy in Colonial Pennsylvania/ Brent E. Barksdale, 1961 (Box 1)
  - The Sin and Pride in "The Pardoner's Tale"/ Betty Kantor; Theology in the Novels of Charles Williams/ Elizabeth Wright, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Love and Marriage in Three English Authors: Chaucer, Milton, and Eliot/ Willene van Loenen Pursell, 1963 (Box 1)
  - A Kingdom Not of This World, A Quest for a Christian Ethic of Revolution with Reference to the Thought of Dostoyevsky, Berdyaev, and Camus/ Garrett Green, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Metaphysical Symbolism in T. S. Eliot's "Four Quartets"/ Ronald Moore, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Bertolt Brechts Hauspostille, Introduction and Selected Translations/ Sidney Hillyer Bremer, 1967 (Box 1)
  - The Entrance Way: The Early Dialectics Within Husserl's Transcendental Phenomenology/ Rick Sprague, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Kierkegaard, Heidegger, and the Concept of Death/ George Hunsinger, 1969 (Box 1)
  - The Motley Crew: Audience as Fool in "Tristam Shandy"/ Barbara Parker, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Surrealism and the Painting of Matta and Magritte/ Irene Clurman, 1970 (Box 1)
  - The Nation Triumphant, The Historical Writings of Henry Adams, Theodore Roosevelt, and Woodrow Wilson/ Stephen A. Moe, 1971 (Box 1)
  - The Dialectics of Eden/ Andrew Walkover, 1974 (Box 1)
  - The Political Economy of Thorstein Veblen and John Kenneth Galbraith/ Jonathan Kahn, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Challenging the Norm: The Dialect Question in the Works of Gadda and Pasolini/ Laurie Jane Anderson, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Haiku in English/ Barbara Ungar, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Approaching Mother Courage or Who's Afraid of Bertolt B.?/ Christopher Michael Sperberg, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Peter Handke: The First Five Plays/ Amy Klatzkin, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Vers Le Theatre Interieur: Elements of Mallarme's Total Art Form/ William Carpenter, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Constructing Reality: Multiple Perspectives in "Ulysses" and "The Waves"/ Anthony Back, 1983 (Box 1)
  - "Die Rose Schonheit Soll Nicht Sterben: Paul Celan's Translations of Shakespeare's Sonnets/ Claire Oshetsky, 1984 (Box 1)
  - An Edge of History: The Implicit Feminism of Doris Lessing's "The Four-Gated City"/ Lisa Maria Hogeland, 1984 (Box 1)
  - The Political Origins of Abstract-Expressionist Art Criticism, The Early Theoretical and Critical Writings of Clement Greenberg and Harold Rosenberg/ James D. Herbert, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Finding a City to Live in: Metaphor and Urban Subjectivity in Baudelaire and Mayakovsky/ Daniel L. Potter, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Elective Affinities: An Essay on Textured Forces and Forms of Desire/ Greg Watkins, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Virginia Woolf: The Politics of Narration/ William R. Handley, 1988 (Box 1)
  - The Significance of Artistic Affirmation in Nietzsche and Joyce/ Maren E. Ormseth, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Time and the Problems of Self-Definition and Uncertainty: Proust, Beckett, and Stravinsky/ Susan Silverman, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Reweaving the Violated Narrative: Strategies for Confronting the Discourse of Political Terror in Luisa Valenzuela's "The Lizard Tail"/ Victoria Guest, 1990 (Box 1)
  - The Opposing Voice: Christine de Pisan's Criticism of Courtly Love/ Sydney E. Smith, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Terrible Swift Sword: The Action of Grace in Three Stories by Flannery O'Connor/ Simon W. Beaven, 1992 (Box 1)
  - The Making of the Cauldron: An Analysis of With and Witchcraft Power in "Macbeth"/ William J. Neuenfeldt, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Homing Pidgins: immigrant Tongues, Immanent Bodies in Abraham Cahan's "Yekl"/ Scott Saul, 1995 (Box 1)
  - The Phenomenon of the Voice and the Listening "I": The Subject in Beckett's Later Prose and Drama/ Ian C. McCrudden, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Umbuji Wa Mnazi and the Poetics of Anthropology/ Nicholas Brown, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Double-Consciousness and the Protean Self in Sylvia Plath's "Ariel"/ Sandra Lim, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Pseudonymous Authorship and Kierkegaard's "Either/Or": The Anxiety of the Aesthetic/ Chi-ming Yang, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Dress Codes: Reading Nineteenth Century Fashion/ Rula Razek, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Cyborgs and Nomads: A Vision of Identity for the Information Age/ Brian Babcock, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Technology Transformation: The Anime Cyberbabe/ Michelle Tung, 2001 (Box 1)
  - An Aesthetic Portrait of Stephen Dedalus: Epiphany and Idolatry/ Karsten Scott Schoellner, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Dark Matters: Death, Language, and Human Limitation in British First World War Poetry/ Matthew D. Coffman, 2003 (Box 2)
  - The Faith of Nonsense: The Analogy of God and the Faith of James Joyce's "Finnegans Wake"/ Josephine Hiu Yen Lau, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Where Nothing Needs to be Said, Heidegger, Walden, and the "Odas Elementales" of Pablo Neruda/ Nico Slate, 2004 (Box 2)
  - As Far as Cho-fu-Sa: The Anxiety of Translation in Ezra Pound's "Cathay"/ Chuan-Mei Lee, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Spaces of Accommodation, a Study of Central Park for the 21st Century/ Casy R. Riffel, 2005 (Box 2)
General note
Special Collections and University Archives materials are stored offsite and must be paged 36-48 hours in advance. For more information on paging collections, see the department's website: http://library.stanford.edu/spc.